

### **ABOUT ME**

A hard working and process oriented Data professional with experience in Data management, Data pre-processing, Data analysis & Machine learning. Experienced in handling a team of data analyst. Looking forward to grow in field of Data Science and machine learning.

#### **SKILLS**

- Excel
- Linux/Unix
- Python
- SQL
- Data Analysis
- NIP
- Classification
- Data Bricks

## **CERTIFICATION**

- Red Hat
- Data Fluency: Exploring & Describing Data
- Data Science Foundations: Fundamentals

### **EDUCATION**

University Of Pune B.Com | 2004 - 2007

## Address

L-3/103, highway housing society, S.V. nagar, Hadapsar, Pune-411013

# CHETAN YADAV

Assistant Manager

+7798931936

yadav.chetan74@gmail.com | Linkedin | Git Hub

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Assitant Manager (ML-Ops) ice mortgage technology | Feb 2021 - Present

- Use ETL concept for data acquisition, data per-processing & data transfer for training ML models
- AWS S3, AWS textract, Data Bricks
- Document Classification using NLP techniques.
- Data preprocessing like text data cleaning, stemming, lemmatization
- Using Text representation techniques like Wrod2vec, Tf-IDF, BOW.
- Using OCR to extract text from documents, Validating results of various OCR technologies
- Build text classification model using Naive Bayes, KNN etc.
- Lead and manage a team of data analyst, data engineers, BA to facilitate and fast track machine learning model building and model validation.

# Team Lead (Doc. Management - Data Analytics and Data Management)

ice mortgage technology | April 2017 - Jan 2021

- Lead and Manage a team of data analyst.
- Functional analysis and implementation of client on boarding & off boarding.
- Use ETL concept & setup for customer data on boarding and off boarding
- Data Analysis to prepare and present management reports.
- Attend requirement meetings, assist customers in crafting their requests, manage team workflow.
- Write and execute Unix shell scripts to copy, move and renames files in bulk.

  Knows how to analyze data within Excel and utilize its functions (VLOOKUP, Pivot Tables, Advanced filtering).
- Communication with customer Support team for scheduling and prioritization.
- Preparing Reports such as Daily status report and weekly status Reports
- Coordinate and collaboration with Operations, App management & Infrastructure teams for smooth implementation of new projects
- Using Zendesk, Salesforce and Ticketing tool for communicating the work status.

### Data Executive (Data Management and Data analytics)

ice mortgage technology | Nov 2014 - March 2017

- Perform pre-processing activities to prep files and use tool to perform bulk import and export
- Monitor production queues during import and export jobs & coordinate with Operations team for capacity utilization.
- Provide regular status updates to stake holders
- Import MySQL data dump in non-prod environment.
- Query database to extract data and perform data analysis to produce monthly management reports.
- Data management which involves data extraction, transformation and loading.